# 粤菜面点里边非常讲究技术的这么一个活儿
Har Gow (Shrimp dumpling) is the type of dim sum required a lot of techniques.
# 三下 三下一张皮
3 slaps, (only need) 3 slaps to make one wrapper
# 这比擀出来的皮还圆
This is rounder than the rolled wrapper
# 非常经典的粤式的小点心 虾饺
Har gow is a classic Cantonese dim sum
# 先把馅儿做一下
Let's make filling first
# 第一  你看我们选的青虾仁
First, see, we choose blue-green colored shrimps
# 一摸很鼓利
You can feel it is firm.
# 一会通过手法来打 给它上劲
Later, I will beat it with a technique to make it bouncy
# 我们给它稍微的吸一下水 蘸干了
Here we dry it with the paper towels
# 这虾线去了吗 去的时候也非常简单
Did you devein the shrimps?  Yes, very simple
# 一揪这小尾巴基本上就出来了
just pull the tail and the vein would come out
# 那么这个我们去好就不用去了
These have already been deveined
# 轻轻的一拍 给两刀 齐活
Slap lightly with the cleaver, chop twice, done,
# 主要是要的大颗粒感
We want the texture of large shrimp pieces
# 切好虾仁咱们放一边
Put aside the chopped pieces
# 然后第二步我们给处理一下小料
Then we will prepare other ingredients
# 肥膘肉一点瘦肉都不要
Just the fat, no lean meat (this is pork)
# 因为虾肉没有脂肪
Because the shrimps have no fat
# 我们正常肥肉是虾是一半
The amount of fat is about 1/2 of the shrimp
# 那么现在从健康的角度来讲 我们稍微给它放成三分之一
Since people care about health these days, we will put in about 1/3
# 就这么大的小丁
Cut into small cubes
# 加一点肥膘肉 增加它的这种香度
The fat will enhance the flavor
# 笋也是切丁
Bamboo shoots will be about 1/3 of the pork fat
# 这个笋放多少呢 放肥肉的三分之一
# 姜要切的特别的细
Dice the ginger very finely
# 但是不能让他嚼到姜粒 姜米
so people will not bite into any ginger.
# 葱也是 得嘞
And same with the scallion
# 下来之后我们就开始打馅儿
Now we will mix the filling
# 处理虾的时候非常有讲究
There is a key point when you prepare the shrimps
# 第一步盐 直接加盐
First let's add salt
# 除了盐之外 白胡椒粉
white pepper
# 盐和胡椒是先放
put in salt and pepper first
# 如果这个虾不是那么太新鲜的话
If the shrimps are not that fresh
# 可以加一点什么 可以加一点蛋清
what can you add? A little egg white
# 但是咱们这虾非常的新鲜 我就不加了
But they are really fresh today, so I won't put in any
# 然后顺时针 咱们开始搅拌
Then stir in a clockwise direction
# 然后我们给它稍微摔打一下
Then let's beat it for a little bit
# 把胶性摔出来
to improve its bounciness.
# 其实就是使大劲几下就出来
Just a few beats will do.
# 这就是盐起的作用
That's is because of the salt
# 这摔到什么程度一定要摔黏了
How hard to you have to beat it? Until it's sticky
# 然后这时候另外把它加味（肥膘丁）
After that, add flavor for pork fat
# 直接单加 我们给它来点 盐
Add a little salt
# 糖 必须得搁糖
Need some sugar
# 鲜味汁 要不搁这个就腻腻歪歪
A little Maggi sauce
# 稍微的来一点生抽 稍微的
A little soy sauce
# 这个时候还有关键的一个 猪油
Some lard is important
# 也是猪肥膘的三分之一左右 三小勺
About 1/3 of the pork fat, about 3 tsp
# 然后我们给它进行一个搅拌 让它起黏
Now we mix again to make it more sticky
# 然后这时候我们把这个笋在放到里面
Now we mix the bamboo shoots
# 葱姜放里边
with scallion and ginger
# 你看我们这个馅儿 这两个都拌好了
Look at the filling, both parts are done
# 这时候再混在一起
Then we put the 2 parts together
# 这时候就不能摔了
No more beating
# 抓 下手抓 抓拌均匀
Just mix it with your hand until it's even. Use a grabbing/clawing motion
# 如果说要不单着弄这和不到一块去
This way everything is mixed evenly
# 肥膘也没味儿
and the pork fat flavor comes out
# 然后我们最后来香油 好勒
Put in a final touch of sesame oil
# 实际上香油调馅儿的时候必须得搁
Sesame oil is important for filling
# 但是要适当
Use the appropriate amount
# 主要吃虾的鲜味
Mainly taste the umaminess of shrimp
# 盐糖 完全可以提出整个虾的鲜味来
Salt and sugar bring out the umaminess of the shrimps
# 这里边不放酒 会影响虾的味
Don't put in any cooking wine, it will affect the flavor of the shrimps
# 尤其是黄酒绝对是不能放的
Especially Huangjiu Cooking wine cannot be used here
# 这馅儿都好了 搁这儿搁这儿
Filling is ready
# 第二步我们开始烫面了
Now let's cook the wheat starch
# 咱们这是小麦提纯 叫澄面
This is the purified wheat, called wheat starch
# 我这准备了一点生粉
This is a little potato starch
# 这生粉是干什么的呢
Why we need potato starch?
# 比如说烫澄面大概是
To cook the wheat starch, it's about
# 半斤的面一斤半的水
500 g starch, 750 g of water
# 因为澄面它吃水特别的多 尤其是包虾饺
Wheat starch takes a lot of water, especially for Har Gow
# 有的师傅喜欢硬点的皮
Some chefs like firmer dough
# 有的师傅喜欢软点的皮
some chefs prefer softer ones
# 拿什么找 加点生粉
Potato starch helps with the texture
# 加上生粉软硬筋性马上就起来
With potato starch, it can be firmer.
# 生粉跟澄面没有什么固定的比例
No fixed ratio of the wheat and potato starch
# 就一点 其实不用都行
Just use a little potato starch, or none at all
# 但是不用它筋度不够 稍微加点生粉
If you don't use it though, it might be too soft.
# 一会在搓的时候我们往里放
We will add some when we knead the dough
# 水开了 我们浇的时候你别一点点浇
water is boiling, don't add it gradually
# 你就大概齐一勺下去 猛一点
Just add it all at once
# 这样它熟的快
to cook it quickly
# 它这个澄面特别吃热水
This wheat starch can absorb a lot of hot water
# 烫完之后你看我们给它充分的搅拌
After adding the hot water, see, we will mix it well
# 这会我们给它捏一捏
then we knead it
# 我觉得今天烫的比较合适
This texture seems fine
# 所以说生粉我先不放 我先搓一搓看
I won't add any potato starch now, I will start kneading and see
# 别怕烫 你别可着一个手这么干
Don't be afraid of the heat. You shouldn't knead it with just one hand,
# 你俩手同时 一下两下三下四下
you need to use both hands, 1,2,3,4...
# 它这样他就有一个缓冲的机会
so your hands can alternate with each other (hence, you will not feel too hot)
# 你看往里叠 然后这会儿这个面出来之后
then fold the dough
# 要往里边加一点猪油
add a little lard
# 一个是调节它的软硬程度
it will make dough softer
# 二一个来讲猪油它会更润
and moist
# 稍微加点猪油
add some lard
# 我看那生粉都用不着了
I think we don't need the potato starch
# 看这软硬程度还挺好 揉的挺好
feels about right, the texture
# 这粤菜里边澄面用的多
In Cantonese cuisine, they use a lot of wheat starch
# 你看这个面你感觉它
you can feel
# 很利落 有弹性 软硬适中
the dough is very elastic and has the right firmness
# 这面就算成了
it's done
# 这馅通过冰箱的冷藏 软硬也适中
the filling has been in the fridge, also at the right firmness
# 胡萝卜丁可以焯水 也可以不焯水
you can blanch the carrot pieces or not, put them in right before wrapping
# 什么时候包再往里放 因为胡萝卜出水
Add it in when you start making the dumpling, because carrot leaks its juice
# 我们就直接放里边了
I am putting them in
# （去皮）小青豆 这也得焯水
and the peas, need to blanch as well.
# 也是给串色用
for color
# 师父 下边我们开始包了
Now we will start wrapping
# 这个包虾饺是粤菜面点里边 非常讲究技术的这么一个活儿
This wrapping part demands high skills
# 首先先取一块澄面
Take a small piece of the dough
# 三下 三下一张皮
3 slaps, (only need) 3 slaps to make one wrapper
# 这个关键点是什么 备块毛巾
What's the key point here? Prepare a towel
# 然后我们用专门的拍皮刀
Use a special cleaver for making wrappers
# 上边一定要刷点油 让它有一点油性
put some oil on your towel
# 刀上弄点油之后是光的
The cleaver will be shiny with the oil
# 按一下 你看
press it, see
# 上面有油 底下没油
it has oil on the surface, but no oil on the bottom
# 你看这就是棒 倍儿圆
See, that's great! so round
# 这比擀出来的皮可圆
It's rounder than a rolled wrapper
# 包的时候 油面朝外不油面朝里
When you wrap the dumpling, the oiled side is facing out
# 搅拌一下
mix it
# 网友朋友们 包虾饺的技术
Friends, you can practice these skills
# 在家没事就可以练一练
at home with your free time
# 上馅儿之后往一边走
Put the filling in and wrap in one direction
# 这个包是这么包 横着推用手指头肚
It's like this, push with the belly of your finger
# 往上捻  捻之后
and pull slightly, then seal the fold
# 这个捻 这个往上跟
when you seal it with one hand, pull the edge with another hand.
# 然后边儿我们给它拿捏一下
finally we press it
# 怎么办呢 去掉
then trim it
# 一个 行了
One done.
# 又一个
one more
# 那么咱们用家里的刀咱们试试
Now we use a regular cleaver
# 网友朋友们在家可以玩一玩
You can try at home
# 也行 看看家里刀也行
see, a regular cleaver works too
# 这小饺子包的 行了
these look good
# 水开了 上屉 小锅正合适
water is boiling, will steam them
# 盖上盖 看看表 四分钟
put the lid on, about 4 min
# 这个虾饺蒸过了也不好 蒸过了裂了
don't oversteam them, they will crack
# 关火 一二三走着
turn off the heat , open up
1,2,3....
# 面点这人时间观念非常强
Pastry chefs are very strict about timing
# 各个饱满 晶莹剔透
Each dumpling is full and crystal clear
# 我们还有一步最重要的是什么 刷点油
Important, brush a little oil on top
# 这样更水晶了 橄榄油
Even more translucent, some olive oil
# 更亮 水晶虾饺么
more shining, crystal shrimp dumpling
# 考验你的馅拌的好不好吃一蘸醋全完
See if it's good, don't dip in vinevar
# 还真够意思了
It is really good
# 看看那个馅儿弹不弹
is the filling chewy?
# 这馅儿拿的味道非常准
very good flavor
# 你师父聪明 一口全装嘴里了
that's smart, put the whole thing in his mouth
# 味儿拿的准
The flavour is very accurate
# 亮子不是单单做菜做得好
Liang Zi cooks well and does pastries well
# 这么多年 能把这个面点
all these years he hasn't forgotten pastry skills
# 这种手艺保持到今天 我觉得也很不易
Impressive
# 不是光把菜做好了 面点也很重要
Cooking and pastries are both important
# 感谢大爷
Thanks to Da Ye
# 感谢大家关注老饭骨
Hope everyone likes and follows Lao Fan Gu
# 也希望网友朋友们
hope our friends also
# 关注焦你亮 教你把菜亮起来
follow "Jiao Ni Liang", teach you make tasty dishes
# 小焦最后还不忘给自己宣传
Xiao Jiao didn't forget marketing himself in the end
# 有网友就一直想让大爷二伯
Our online friends want Da Ye and Er Bai
# 讲讲各种淀粉的用途
talk about how to use different kinds of starch
# 淀粉分不少种
There are many kinds of starch
# 第一就是我们常见的生粉
The first is the common starch
# 后边的还有绿豆淀粉
There are also mung bean starch
# 有玉米淀粉
corn starch
# 有藕粉
lotus root starch
# 有菱角粉
water caltrop strach
# 有马蹄粉
water chestnut starch
# 有白薯粉
sweet potato starch
# 有土豆粉
potato starch
# 这些淀粉
These starches
# 它的性能不一样
are different on their performance.
# 先说一种 第一种生粉
First one, common starch
# 它叫多链淀粉
It's called amylopectin
# 像其他的淀粉叫直链淀粉
other starches, called amylose
# 这两个区别在哪呢
What's the difference?
# 比如说我们做一个汤
For example, we make a soup
# 做汤的
Making soup
# 像一些烩菜
Like some stew
# 勾汁明汁亮芡的
need to make the slurry
# 比如酸辣汤
Such as hot and sour soup
# 或者做一个浓汁
Or make a thick sauce
# 但是不是很浓的
But not very thick
# 就是像比米汤芡稍微的浓厚一点
It's like a little thicker than rice soup
# 我们一般都采用生粉
We generally use common starch
# 它比较
It is relatively
# 透亮
Translucent
# 粘稠
Sticky
# 但是我们要炒菜用
But we want to cook
# 像北方
Like the North
# 像川菜
Like Sichuan cuisine
# 鲁菜
or Shandong cuisine
# 淮扬菜
or Huaiyang cuisine
# 大部分都用绿豆淀粉
Most of them use mung bean starch
# 或者是玉米淀粉
Or corn starch
# 有的地区
Some areas
# 像川菜用的白薯粉
Like the sweet potato flour used in Sichuan cuisine
# 土豆粉
potato starch
# 像马蹄粉和藕粉
Like water chestnut starch and lotus root starch
# 还有菱角粉
and water caltrop strach
# 都是一般做甜品
They are generally used for making desserts
# 要用的
To use
# 因为它有一种特殊的香味
# 第二个特点
The second feature
# 如果说生粉
If you say common starch
# 我们把这芡勾得太浓了
the slurry is too thick
# 我们放水想把它溶解一下
We want to dissolve it with water
# 它溶解不了
It can't dissolve
# 水还是水
Water is still water
# 芡还是芡
thick slurry is still thick
# 但是要像玉米淀粉
But like cornstarch
# 绿豆淀粉
Mung bean starch
# 还有其他淀粉
other starches
# 如果芡勾浓了勾了一坨子
If the slurry is too thick
# 我们加点水
You add some water
# 拿勺子一加热
Take the spoon and heat it up
# 一搅
stir it
# 他这个淀粉就溶解了
the starch can dissolve in the water
# 所以
so
# 它能溶解
# 生粉不容易溶解
common starch is hard to dissolve
# 这是
that is
# 多链淀粉和直链淀粉的区别
The difference between amylopectin and amylose